Carolyn Gabel-Brett Feminist and LGBT Collections. GLBTQ.2012.03
GLBTQ Archives
- Series IX: Connecticut Stonewall Congress
  - Bonnie Glasser, Student Intern-Stonewall Foundation - evaluation form, faxes, correspondence, newspaper articles, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Connecticut Stonewall Foundation/Hartford Gay and Lesbian Health Collective 20th anniversary exhibit at Central CT State University February 2, 2003 - message from creator Richard Nelson (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Connecticut Stonewall Foundation Annual Meeting, April 12, 2004 - correspondence, notes, by-laws, summary of activities (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Series X: Hate Crimes
  - Hate Crimes - articles, reports, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund (CWEALF) Hate Crimes Project - 13th Annual Awards Dinner program, business listing, community organization listing, Connecticut Pride Link Advisory Committee agenda, grant submitted for Connecticut Pride Link database for Connecticut residents to network, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - National Hate Crimes Legislation - article, fact sheet, press release, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund (CWEALF) - grant submission to Gill Foundation regarding funding for hate crimes prevention program along with continued funding of in-place programs, related articles and correspondence regarding hate crimes and legislation, "Legal Rights of Lesbians, Gay Men, and Bisexuals in Connecticut", 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Stop the Hate: An Inter-faith Forum and Press Conference - press releases (protest by Westboro Baptist Church in Hartford and responses), official statement with clergy and community leaders' signatures, November 22, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Eminem's Hate Lyrics - press conference flyers and photographs, July 21, 2000; news articles, media list, correspondence, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Condemning Hate Speech by Eminem - press kit, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights Hate Crimes Coalition: United Against Hate Campaign - correspondence, alleged "gay bashing" at Ocean Beach, New London, CT, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights (CCLGCR) Hate Crimes Legislation: "An Act Concerning Intimidation Based on Bigotry or Bias" - correspondence, action alerts, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - "Hate Crimes Prevention Act" - correspondence, action alert, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Series XI: Political and Legislative Issues
  - Connecticut Women's Political Caucus - newsletters, notes, minutes, membership list, clippings, 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut Women's Political Caucus - meeting minutes, annual report, fact sheets, reports, convention agenda, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Connecticut Women's Political Caucus candidate polling project - correspondence, questionnaire, results, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut Women's Political Caucus candidate polling project - completed questionnaires, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut Women's Political Caucus - articles, flyers, legislative proposals, newsletters, correspondence, candidate questionnaire, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut Women's Political Caucus legislative issues - bills, vote counts, notes, correspondence, articles, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - William Wollenberg Transcripts - proceedings, testimony, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - William Wollenberg Transcripts - proceedings, testimony, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - William Wollenberg Transcripts - testimony, notes, articles, appellate decisions, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - William Wollenberg Transcripts - correspondence, transcripts, articles, notes, testimony, flyer, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miles Rapoport "Women for Rapoport Fundraiser" - emails, tickets, poster, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Miles Rapoport articles for the American Prospect - draft, revisions, correspondence, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Democracy Works - correspondence, orders, notes, newsletter, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Democracy Works fundraising - list, briefing sheet, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Democracy Works - miscellanea, correspondence, notes, agenda, workshop information, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Democracy Works: Restoration of Voting Rights Project - symposium agenda, program, brochures, correspondence, articles, attendees list, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Democracy Works: University of Connecticut Student Interns - orientation materials, notes, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Democracy Works: Election Day Voter Registration Workshop - invitation, fact sheets, agenda, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Democracy Works: Budget Meeting with Senator Kevin Sullivan - correspondence, phone and address lists, notes, mailings, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit Lobby Day - notes, sign-up sheets, flyers, program, March 2001 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit - testimony before the Human Services Committee and the Appropriations Committee, January 2006 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit Media/Communitcations - notes, correspondence, articles, editorial, January 2006-April 2006 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit - bills and timetable, mayor's press conference notes, Connecticut Economic Security Act, Legal Assistance Resource Center of Connecticut, February 2006-March 2006 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit - Connecticut Association for Human Services grant application, Legislative Outreach Campaign plan and activities, March 2006 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit Community Partners - correspondence, notes, March 2006-April 2006 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit: Family Economic Security Action Alerts - correspondence, notes, March 2006-April 2006 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit - Connecticut Association for Human Services invoices, pay stubs, consulting contract, April 2006 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Earned Income Tax Credit - Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) press conference, April 2006 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Ned Lamont for Senate/Connecticut Choice Voice Fundraiser - notes, advertisements, correspondence, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Ned Lamont for Senate/Equality CT - notes, articles, correspondence, vote counts, flyers, petitions, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Ned Lamont for Senate/Choice 2006 - flyers, bumper sticker, voter registration form, list of registrars, notes (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Miscellanea - legislative proposals, Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights brochure, photographs with Toby Moffett, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Lobbying and Legislative Action - correspondence, fact sheet, newsletter, flyer, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - People for Change Campaign - plan, district street listing, notes, flyers, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Presidential Inauguration of William Jefferson Clinton - invitation, tickets, Gay and Lesbian Inaugural Celebration program and portrait, letter of nomination for Inaugural Reception honoree, clipping, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Political Research Associates correspondence, 1996; "How Democracy Works," 1996; election information, 1998; Village Voice Education Supplement, 1998, 1996, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Legislative Electoral Assistance Project (LEAP) - planning agenda, memoranda, activities, Social and Economic Justice Coalition Project, Northeast Action News, 1996-1999 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Debt Retirement - meeting notes, agenda, minutes, correspondence, lists, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Miscellanea - brochures, event agendas, candidate forum schedule, jury duty summons, flight itinerary, symposium notice, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Election Day Registration/Campaign Finance Reform - testimony before Government, Administration, and Elections Committee, announcement, articles, bills, fact sheets, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Hilltop Brigade campaign volunteers - fact sheet, notes, correspondence, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Beth Bye for State Representative Campaign - notes, minutes, article, vote count, survey results, phone list, correspondence, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Series XII: United Way and Latinos/as Contra SIDA
  - United Way Allocations Committee - agency reviews, correspondence, agendas, budget requests, summaries, flyers, reports, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - United Way Site Visit Committee - reports, correspondence, budget requests, schedule, forms, maps, flyers, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - United Way/La Casa de Puerto Rico, Inc. - correspondence, financial statements, tax forms, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - United Way Lesbian and Gay Issues - notes, correspondence, forms, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA - correspondence, board of directors minutes and agenda, action alert, newsletter, budget, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA Finance Committee - leadership and training materials, reports, notes, minutes, agendas, correspondence, budget spreadsheets, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA - annual report minutes, membership, budget, donations, clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA Annual Report 1993 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA - minutes, agendas, correspondence, policies and procedures, memoranda, budget worksheets, article, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA Finance and Development Committee - minutes, agenda, budget worksheet, resumes, correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA - finance committee and board minutes, agenda; Project J.U.M.P.P. (Jovenes Unidos Movilizados Para Prevencion) reports, newsletter, notes, memoranda, article, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA Board, Personnel, and Nomination Committee - event programs, notes, lists, action alert flyers, memoranda, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA Development Committee - memoranda, notes, correspondence, development worksheets, agendas, minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA Board of Directors - agendas, minutes, reports, budget spreadsheets, articles, flyers, memoranda, notes, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA Finance Committee - income worksheets, budgets, notes, memoranda, correspondence, agenda, minutes, budget spreadsheets, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Latinos/as Contra SIDA Board of Directors - agendas, minutes, notes, memoranda, correspondence, newsletters, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Series XIII: Posters
  - Garlic. Chez Panisse Garlic Festival. Berkeley, David Lance Goines, 1979. Autographed on the reverse side by Tirzah, Jenifer, Lesley, Pura and Stonewall Congress. 50.5 x 70.5 cm. (Box 10)
  - Gertrude and Alice. Diana Souhami. Pandora, Imprint of Harper Collins, n.d. 40 x 55 cm. (3 copies), undated (Box 10)
  - Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Civil Rights. 1997 Legislative Summary. 45.5 x 60.5 cm. (Box 10)
  - Improving Our Services Creating Safe Support Space.. .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 6.5 cm. (Box 10)
  - Screening for Woman to Woman Battering.. .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm. (Box 10)
  - Effects of Homophobia, Bi-Phobia, "Coming Out/Closeted Issues".. .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm. (Box 10)
  - Differences between S/M and Battering.. .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm. (Box 10)
  - Myths about Woman to Woman Battering.. .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm. (Box 10)
  - Domestic Violence in Same-Gender Relationships.. .Hartford, [1997] 45.5 x 60.5 cm. (Box 10)
  - "Imogene Knode" poem by Olga Broumas, 14 x 42 cm., 1978 (Box 10)
  - "Activist Women Tell Their Stories," featuring Carolyn Gabel-Brett; Trinity College, Hartford, CT, n.d. 28 x 42 cm., undated (Box 10)
  - Daedalus Productions of New York Presents "For Colored Girls who have Considered Suicide when the Rainbow is Enuf" a play by Ntozake Shange, 28 x 42 cm., 1982 (Box 10)
  - Wallflower Order Dance Collective, A Benefit for Interval House Shelter for Battered Women, n.d. 29 x 44 cm., undated (Box 10)
  - Institute for Women of Color, "Building a Colorful Coalition," autographed by Marion C. Martinez, 28 x 42 cm., 1982 (Box 10)
  - Holly Near and Cris Williamson, A Benefit Concert for the Mediation and Training Collaborative, Franklin Community Action Corporation, autographed by Holly Near and Cris Williamson, 26.5 x 41 cm., 2002 (Box 10)
  - Women's Studies Posters and Flyers for Past CCSU Women's Studies Events (Box 10)
    - Women in Performing Arts, 45 x 30 cm., 1985 (Box 10)
    - Women in Sports, 45 x 30 cm., 1985 (Box 10)
    - Some Firsts for Women, 45 x 30 cm., 1985 (Box 10)
    - Women in Science, 45 x 30 cm., 1985 (Box 10)
    - The Common Woman, 45 x 30 cm., 1985 (Box 10)
    - Women in Government, 45 x 30 cm., 1985 (Box 10)
    - Women in Art and Literature, 45 x 30 cm., 1985 (Box 10)
    - Women in Social Reform, 45 x 30 cm., 1985 (Box 10)
    - Secretary of Labor Frances Perkins, Author of Social Security, TABS: Aids for Ending Sexism in School, 28 x 43 cm., 1980 (Box 10)
    - Congressional Resolution Designating the Month of March as "Women's History Month," n.d. 28 x 42.5 cm., undated (Box 10)
    - The Committee on the Concerns of Women presents the Annual Women's History Luncheon "A Celebration of Women in the Arts," 28 x 42 cm., 1994 (Box 10)
    - Debate: Nancy Johnson, Charlotte Koskoff, Timothy Knibbs - Student Center Ballroom, CCSU, 28 x 42 cm., 1996 (Box 10)
    - Women's History Month Luncheon: Laughter: RX for Survival, co-sponsored by the Committee on the Concerns of Women, Women's Studies, and the Ruth Boyea Women's Center, n.d. 28 x 42 cm., undated (Box 10)
    - Women's History Month activities: Luncheon, Lecture Series, and Performance, n.d., 28 x 42 cm., undated (Box 10)
    - Take Back the Night: Rally and March Against Sexual Assault, CCSU, 28 x 42 cm., 1996 (Box 10)
    - The CCSU Committee on the Concerns of Women presents "Laughter and Tears: A Celebration of Women Past and Present," n.d. 28 x42 cm., undated (Box 10)
    - Women's Studies Picnic to Celebrate the 75th Anniversary of Women's Suffrage, 26.5 x 40.5 cm., 1995 (Box 10)
    - An Illustrated Timeline of the Woman Suffrage Movement produced by the National Women's History Project, set of 8 posters, 28 x 42 cm., 1994 (Box 10)
  - Feminist and Lesbian Posters (Box 10)
    - Henrietta Szold, Women of Valor series produced by The Jewish Women's Archive and Ma'yan: The Jewish Women's Project, n.d. 45 x 60 cm., undated (Box 10)
    - Glikl bas Judah of Hameln, Women of Valor series produced by The Jewish Women's Archive and Ma'yan: The Jewish Women's Project, n.d. 45 x 60 cm., undated (Box 10)
    - Rose Schneiderman, Women of Valor series produced by The Jewish Women's Archive and Ma'yan: The Jewish Women's Project, n.d. 45 x 60 cm., undated (Box 10)
    - Katherine Dunham by Christine Engle Eber, n.d. 43 x 55.5 cm., undated (Box 10)
    - Hopi Corn Grinding Song by Christine Engle Eber, 43 x 56 cm., 1979 (Box 10)
    - An Unauthorised Interview Between The Suffragists and The Statue of Liberty by Alice Duer Miller from Women are People! (1917), 35 x 45 cm., 1977 (Box 10)
    - Maria Mitchell quote by Christine Engle Eber, 55 x 43 cm., 1975 (Box 10)
    - Elizabeth Cady Stanton triangular felt pennant from The National Women's Hall of Fame, n.d. 63 x 22 cm., undated (Box 10)
- Series XIV: Miscellaneous
  - VHS tape: Andrew Sullivan "Virtually Normal" 1 hour, n.d., undated (Box 11)
  - VHS tape: "A Matter of Culture" 15 minutes, n.d., undated (Box 11)
  - VHS tape: "G/L channel 6 story!!" n.d., undated (Box 11)
  - VHS tape: "CCADV/CIGNA Carolyn 1998" (Box 11)
  - DVD "Native Americans in Philanthropy" nativephilanthropy.org, n.d., undated (Box 11)
  - Video tape (reel-to-reel) "Policy and Licensing-Training Seminar" Gay-Lesbian Alliance, January 29, 1981, 2 reels (Box 11)
  - Framed picture of Senator Joe Lieberman with quotation "I don't have time for this, sweetheart." in response to Carolyn Gabel-Brett's questioning him about his position on same-sex marriage, n.d., 23 x 28.5 cm., undated (Box 11)
  - Stickers (Box 11)
    - White rectangle, red, white, and blue lettering "Equality Begins at Home" National Gay and Lesbian Task Force, Federation of LGBT Statewide Political Organizations, March 21-27, 1999, 4 x 2.5 cm. (Box 11)
    - White circle with picture of a clothes hanger outlined in red with a red diagonal line through it, n.d., 4 x 4 cm., undated (Box 11)
    - Yellow circle with "Equality" written in black, n.d., 7 cm., undated (Box 11)
    - Red circle with "Making Women Visible Day" written in white, n.d., 9 x 7.3 cm., undated (Box 11)
    - White square, "This Home's Privacy is Protected by the ACLU," n.d., 7.6 x 7.6 cm., undated (Box 11)
    - Yellow rectangle with blue lettering, "Keep Your Laws off my Body" National Organization for Women, n.d., 23 x 7.5 cm., undated (Box 11)
    - White rectangle with red, white, and blue lettering "It's a Man's World Unless Women Vote" CT Permanent Commission on the status of Women, n.d., 29 x 7.5 cm., undated (Box 11)
  - Buttons (Box 11)
    - White rectangle, red, white, and blue lettering "Equality Begins at Home" National Gay and Lesbian Task Force, Federation of LGBT Statewide Political Organizations, March 21-27, 1999, 5 x 4 cm., 3 buttons (Box 11)
    - Blue circle with white lettering "Gay and Lesbian Voters for Clinton Gore" Human Rights Campaign Fund, n.d., 6.5 cm., undated (Box 11)
  - Directories, booklets, pamphlets (Box 11)
    - Directory of Connecticut's Federal and State Elected Officials 1999-2000, The League of Women Voters of Connecticut Education Fund, Inc., 10 x 22 cm., 25 pages (Box 11)
    - Directory of Connecticut's Federal and State Elected Officials 2001-2002, The League of Women Voters of Connecticut Education Fund, Inc., 10 x 22 cm., 25 pages (Box 11)
    - Booklet "People Have the Power Rally" Connecticut Progressive Directory, 13.7 x 21 cm., 16 pages, 2002 (Box 11)
    - Booklet "Connecticut Pridelink 2000, a resource guide of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Organizations," Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund, 10 x 21.5 cm., 50 pages (Box 11)
    - Booklet "Universal Declaration of Human Rights, National Center for Human Rights Education," 9.5 x 12.7 cm., [20 pages], undated (Box 11)
    - Booklet "Confronting Homophobia: Notes on Creating a Lesbian Community" by Bernice Goodman, A Matter of LIfe, National Gay Health Coalition Educational Foundation, 16 x 21 cm., 12 pages, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Companions: A dating service formed exclusively for lesbians and gay males", undated (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "There are 13 Votes Between Equality and You..." National Women's Political Caucus Equal Rights Amendment Fund, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Gender Identity Clinic of New England, Information presented by the Twenty Club", 2004 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Summit Women's Center West: Quality gynecological and counseling services, West Hartford", undated (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Why are Parents, Teenagers, Teachers... Fighting the Family Protection Act?" National Coalition to Stop the FPA (Family Protection Act), undated (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Why are Women Joinng the National Gay Task Force?" 2 copies, undated (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Abortion, Legal Since 1973, yet in Connecticut, the Constitution State..." Conn-NARAL (National Abortion Rights Action League), 1978 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Abortion, Legal Since 1973, yet in Connecticut, the Constitution State..." Conn-NARAL (National Abortion Rights Action League), 1979 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "YWCA Sexual Assault Crisis Service 24 Hour Hot LIne", undated (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Know Your Rights: What to do if You're Stopped by the Police, the FBI, the INS, or the Customs Service," published by the ACLU, updated December 2001 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Community Works of Connecticut: Give for Change", undated (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Connecticut General Assembly of 1981" Conn-NARAL (National Abortion Rights Action League) (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "The Connecticut Task Force on Abused Women", undated (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Three Extraordinary Women," The University of Tennessee Press, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "Women in China," Philo Press, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "A Celebration of Our Healing," YWCA of Greater New Haven, undated (Box 11)
    - Pamphlet "The Fourth National Lesbian/Gay Health Conference," University of Houston, undated (Box 11)